(
"ai_sub_version": "2.5.0",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 2,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 12,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"web_search_tool": "duckduckgo",
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
みなさーん！風真いろは生誕ライブ2025
Everyone! Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2025!
来てくださりまして、ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming!
全力で楽しんでってくださいね！
Please enjoy yourselves to the fullest!
想像なんてしてなかった
I never imagined
現状 君もそう思った？
this situation. Did you feel the same?
“最高”で止まらないように
So that we don't stop at "the best,"
更新したい
I want to keep updating.
叶えたい夢まであとどれくらい？
How much longer until the dream I want to fulfill?
誰も行ったことがない場所へ
To a place where no one has ever been before.
たどり着くまでは“僕ら止まれない”
Until we get there, "we can't stop."
たぶんしんどいけど、どうかよろしくね
It might be tough, but please stay with me.
ねえねえ たまにメーデー
Hey, hey, sometimes a mayday,
僕だけじゃ作れないモノ
things I can't create on my own.
僕とか君とかあたしとか
Like me, and you, and I,
恋とか愛とかまとめて全部
like love and affection, all of it together.
君を置いてどこかに行っちゃうとか
Leaving you behind and going somewhere else...
ありえないよ！
That's impossible!
君がくれた音に
In the sound you gave me,
弾けた火花に
in the sparks that flew,
はじめましてから ずっと恋しちゃってるんだよ
I've been in love ever since we first met.
君のいない未来考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これから先も二人がいいじゃん
From now on, the two of us would be better, wouldn't it?
一途になるほど
The more devoted I became,
逃げ出したくなったよ
the more I wanted to run away.
散々名前を呼んでくれてありがとう
Thank you for calling my name so many times.
君のいない未来考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これから先も二人で それがいいじゃん
From now on, the two of us together—that's how it should be.
妄想 膨らんでくストーリー
A delusion, an expanding story.
感傷 やけに凹んじゃって
Sentimentality, I feel quite down.
最初 求めすぎは野暮
At first, asking for too much is tacky.
終わんない愛の連盟 どうでしょう？
The endless alliance of love, how about it?
ねえねえ おいでメーデー
Hey, hey, come here, mayday.
僕が君にできること
The things I can do for you,
まだまだまだまだあるけど踊ろう
there's still so much more, so let's dance.
聞かせたいから内緒なのだ
I want you to hear it, so it's a secret.
君の愛がいつか勝っちゃうこと
That your love will one day win.
許さないよ
I won't allow it.
君以外は
Anything but you
ヤバ、わがままは
Is bad; my selfishness is
ただ、変わらない
Just unchanging.
ときめきを
This heartbeat...
合唱しちゃうのは
singing it in chorus
バカ
Is stupid.
君がくれた音に
In the sound you gave me,
弾けた火花に
in the sparks that flew,
初めましてから
from our first 'nice to meet you,'
ずっと恋しちゃってるんだよ
I've been in love with you all along.
君のいない未来考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これから先も二人がいいじゃん
From now on, the two of us would be better.
道連れになるほど
So much so that I'd take you with me,
逃げたくもなったよ
I even wanted to run away.
散々な僕のこと
For calling out to my wretched self,
呼んでくれてありがとう
thank you.
君のいない未来考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これから先も二人でそれがいいじゃん
From now on, let's be together; that would be best.
乙女解剖であそぼうよ
Let's play with Maiden Dissection,
ドキドキしたいじゃんか
we want our hearts to race, right?
誰だって、判をもう一回
Anyone, give me the stamp one more time.
おかしくなっちゃった痛み合いたい
I want to share the pain of going crazy.
傷が離れない
The scars won't leave.
僕らヴァンパイア
We are Vampires,
いいよ、吸っちゃっていいよ
it's okay, you can suck my blood.
もう無理、もう無理だって
I can't anymore, I can't anymore, because
悪い子じゃない
I'm not a bad child.
こんな歌ったんだって
Even if I sang like this,
君が輝けるように
I hope you can shine.
はい！というわけで、皆殿！こんばんでござる！
Yes! And so, everyone! Good evening!
ホロライブ6期生、つよつよかっこいい護衛侍、風真いろはでござる！
From Hololive's 6th Generation, the strong and cool bodyguard samurai, Kazama Iroha!
はい。今年の誕生日一発目は、DECO*27さんの合言葉シリーズ4、合言葉IVを歌って躍らせていただきました！
Yes. For the first part of this year's birthday, I sang and danced to DECO*27's 'Words of Love' series 4, 'Aikotoba IV'!
拍手いっぱい来てる！みんな、ありがとう！ギフトとかスパチャもありがとうございます。
So many applauses! Thank you, everyone! Thank you for the gifts and Super Chats too.
はい。今日ね、たくさん歌って躍らせていただくんですけど、感想とか、あと実況、ソ、ソ、ソ、とかは...
Yes. I'll be singing and dancing a lot today, so for your thoughts and live-tweeting...
ここ！#風真いろは生誕LIVE2025 でたくさんポストしてください。
Here! Please post a lot using the hashtag #KazamaIrohaBirthdayLIVE2025.
振り返る時に見に行きますからね！
I'll go take a look when I look back on today!
そして、今回なんと誕生日用のステージを作っていただきました！
And, for this occasion, they actually made a birthday stage for me!
可愛い！ぽこさん、お前ディスプレイになったんか。
It's so cute! Poco-san, you've turned into a display?
いや、どこに行ってたかと思ったらディスプレイになっとりました。はい。
I was wondering where you went, and you were a display. Yes.
そして後ろにも書いてあります。今回の風真いろはのライブタイトル、'Reversible'になってます。
And it's written behind me too. This Kazama Iroha live title is 'Reversible'.
素敵なロゴ、柊木先生ありがとうございました。こちらですね、
A wonderful logo; thank you, Hiiragi-sensei. This is...
みんな昨日のカウントダウン配信では、ちょっと「ありゃ？」みたいな、どんなだろうってまだ「？」な方が多かったと思うんですが、
I think many of you were a bit like 'Huh?' or 'What's it like?' during yesterday's countdown stream,
今回これ全編見てもらったらちゃんとわかるようになっておりますので、最後までお楽しみください。
but if you watch the whole thing today, it'll all make sense, so please enjoy until the end.
そして、事前にお伝えしていました通り、今回風真いろは、100万人記念グッズが発売決定しました！
And, as I announced beforehand, Kazama Iroha's 1 million subscriber commemorative merchandise is now on sale!
うわー、いきなり来るよ。というわけで今日は本当にまた告知溜めすぎてるので、ちょいちょい挟んでいきたいと思います。
Whoa, it's coming out of nowhere. So, I have way too many announcements again today, so I'll be sprinkling them in.
はい。風真いろは100万人記念グッズこちらです。それでは詳細見ていきましょう。
Yes. Here are the Kazama Iroha 1 million subscriber commemorative goods. Let's look at the details.
はい。まずは海坊主ママが描いてくださった素敵なアクリルスタンド。
First, a wonderful acrylic stand illustrated by Umibouzu-mama.
アクリルスタンドにこう、風真も一筆添えさせていただいておりますので、ぜひ皆様こちらぜひお手にとっていただいて、メッセージじっくり読んでください。ぽこべえもいます。
I've added a handwritten message to the acrylic stand, so please get one and read the message carefully. Pokobe is there too.
そして次がこちら。パブ、パブミ、パブミラー！すごいちょっと言いづらいんだよね、これリハの時から思ってたんですけど、
Next is this. A pub, pub-mi, pub mirror! It's actually a bit hard to say; I've been thinking that since the rehearsals.
はい。パブミラーです。結構大きいです。風真が出したグッズの中でもこう、硬くてなんかこの立て掛ける系のなかで、
Yes. A pub mirror. It's quite big. Among the goods I've released, among the hard, stand-up types...
タオルとかはあったけどかなり大きめになってますので、皆様ぜひこちらもメッセージ一筆書かせていただいておりますので、ぜひ飾ってもらえたら嬉しいです。そしてそして次、
we've had towels and such, but this is quite large, and I've written a message on this too, so I'd be happy if you'd display it. And next,
はい。ランダムラバーストラップ。今回は100万人にちなみまして、風真いろは、今オリジナル曲複数出させていただいているんですけども、
Yes. Random rubber straps. This time, to commemorate the 1 million subscribers, since I have several original songs out now,
そちらのモチーフ衣装をラバーストラップにさせていただきました。
I've made rubber straps of the motif outfits from those songs.
なので風真いろは等ね、
So, like the Kazama Iroha items,
実はなかなかグッズがなかったんですけど、
we actually haven't had much merch,
今回のために作らせていただきました。
but I had these made for this occasion.
ぜひね、みんな色々集めて痛バとかの制作に
Please collect them and use them
役立てていただければと思います！
to create things like 'ita-bags'!
次！
Next!
カードホルダー！
Card holder!
昨今皆さんホロカとかね、色んなカードとか
With 'Holo-Cards' and various other
チェキ風のグッズが出ておりますので、
Cheki-style goods coming out lately,
ついに作りました！ぽこべぇのカードホルダーです！
I finally made a Pokobe card holder!
定期入れにしてもよし、学生さんに
You can use it for your pass,
使っていただけたら嬉しいです。
and I'd be happy if students used it too.
ぜひ皆さんお気に入りの風真のカードとか飾ってくださいね！
Please display your favorite Kazama cards!
さあ！それでは次！
All right! Moving on!
こちらフルセットこのようになっておりまして、
Here's what the full set looks like,
そして今回購入特典は、はい！
and the purchase bonus this time is...
うみぼうずママ描き下ろしのステッカーにさせていただきました！
A sticker newly illustrated by Umibozu-mama!
今回はですね、こちら直筆サインの数量限定版はありませんので、
There's no limited quantity version
あの皆さん安心してゆっくり買ってくださいね。
so everyone can take their time buying them.
はい！というわけで、100万人記念グッズ紹介でございました！
So, that was the 1-million-sub merch intro!
うわあ、ドキドキして、なんか結構、あ、安心しきってるんですけど、
Wow, I was so nervous, but now I'm feeling quite relieved...
あの、もうこれだけじゃなくてですね、後半もあの告知がありすぎて
But that's not all! There are so many announcements
頑張って入れるしかなかったぐらいにはいっぱいあるんで、告知いっぱいあります。
in the second half that I had to cram them in. Lots of news!
なので、あの皆さん絶対に見逃さないでください。
So please, everyone, don't miss a single one.
で、もうトレンド1位なんですか！？
Wait, we're already #1 on trending!?
始まったばっかりだよ！いいの！？
We just started! Is this for real!?
みんなありがとう！うそ！
Thank you, everyone! No way!
みんなありがとうございます！
Thank you all so much!
いや、すごい、めっちゃ、こんなに早くなると思わんくて
Wow, this is amazing. I didn't think it would happen so fast.
皆さんのおかげです。本当にありがとうございます！
It's all thanks to you. Thank you so much!
で、ちょっとお水飲んで、次の曲バシバシ行きたいと思います。
Now, let me have some water, and then we'll dive into the next song.
お待たせしました。
Sorry to keep you waiting.
お水いっぱい飲んだので、
I've had plenty of water,
この力をそのまま全てフルパワーで出力いたします！
so I'm going to release all that energy at full power!
それでは皆殿、次の曲聞いてください。
Now then, everyone, please listen to the next song.
大きな愛でもてなして！
Entertain me with great love!
大きな愛でもてなして
Entertain me with great love
そこんとこ大事なことよ
That's the important part, you know
大きな愛でもてなして
Entertain me with great love
わがままでないのよ オホホ
I'm not being selfish, oh-ho-ho
私わかったの
I've come to realize
寂しがりやだと
that I'm a lonely person
泣きそうよ
I feel like crying
一日の間でも
Even in just a single day
告白をしたり
Whether confessing my love
キスしたり
or kissing,
一日は大人より
a day is much deeper for me
相当濃いのです
than it is for an adult
相当長いのです そうみたい
It's quite long, it seems
大きな愛でもてなして
Entertain me with great love
そこんとこ気ままじゃ嫌よ
I don't like it when you're just doing as you please
大きな愛でもてなして
Entertain me with great love
ごゆっくりなさって 良いわ
Take your time, it's fine
みんな知らんぷり
Everyone's feigning ignorance...
他人事だと
...like it's someone else's business
違うのよ
But that's not it
明日はまた新しい
Tomorrow, if there's another...
恋愛があれば 逆らえ
...new love, I can't resist it
大人より率直に
More honestly than an adult,
たくさん恋できちゃう
I can fall in love over and over
たくさん恋できちゃう そうみたい
I can fall in love over and over, it seems
明日はまた新しい
Tomorrow, if there's another...
恋愛があれば 逆らえ
...new love, I can't resist it
大人より 遠くで
From further away than adults
もっと 遠くに
Even further away
たくさん 恋でしちゃう
Many loves come to me
そういうみたい
That's how it seems
大きな愛で もてなして
Treating you to big love
ありえない幻想
Unbelievable fantasy
あふれだす妄想
Overflowing delusions
君以外全部 いらないわ
I don't need anything but you
息をするように 嘘ついても
Even if I lie as easily as I breathe
あたしやっぱり いらない子？
Am I really an unwanted child after all?
こぼれだしちゃった 承認欲求
My desire for approval has spilled over
もっとココロ 満たしてよ
Fill my heart even more
アスパルテーム 甘い夢
Aspartame, a sweet dream
あたしだけに 愛をください
Please give your love only to me
愛も無理も罪も恋して愛して 救済執行ばっか
Love, impossibility, sin; loving and being loved, just seeking salvation
好きって言ってよ？
Tell me you love me?
ありえない幻想
Unbelievable fantasy
あふれだす妄想
Overflowing delusions
止まんない不安が 散らばって
Unstoppable anxieties are scattered
求めすぎて 愛情
Seeking too much affection
隠してる 絶望
Hidden despair
君以外全部 いらないわ
I don't need anything but you
誰のこと見てんの？
Who are you looking at?
こういうの好きなの？
Do you like this kind of thing?
DDとかガチで やめてください
Please, seriously stop being a fan of everyone
かわいくなりたい
I want to be cute
キラキラしてたい
I want to sparkle
もっともっとガチで 褒めてください
Please, more and more seriously, praise me
毎日惨状
Every day is a disaster
あけちゃうシャンパン
Opening champagne
今夜も配信 来てくれるよね？
You'll come to the stream tonight too, right?
独占させてよ
Let me have you all to myself
本命なんでしょ？
I'm your number one, right?
もっともっとガチで 推してください
Please, more and more seriously, support me
飲みすぎ注意 オーバードーズ
Be careful of drinking too much, overdose
クラクラさせて いつだって
Make me dizzy, always
愛も無理も上がり下がりで 救済執行ばっか
Love, impossibility, ups and downs; just seeking salvation
好きって言わせて？
Let me say I love you?
噛みついた衝動
The impulse that bit
戻れない少女
The girl who can't go back
たまんないミッドナイト 指が絡まって
Unbearable midnight, fingers intertwined
ときめいた表情
A fluttering expression
何も言わないで
Don't say anything
君だけがきっと 王子様
You are surely the only prince for me
ありえない幻想
Unbelievable fantasy
あふれだす妄想
Overflowing delusions
止まんない不安が 散らばって
Unstoppable anxieties are scattered
求めすぎて 愛情
Seeking too much affection
隠してる 絶望
Hidden despair
君以外全部 いらないわ
I don't need anything but you
あたしだけずっと 追いかけて！
Keep chasing after only me forever!
ねえ もう待てないの
Hey, I can't wait anymore
君以外全部 いらないわ
I don't need anything but you
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Please never quit being an idol
輝いてる君を 見たい
I want to see you shining
もっと ずっと ずっと ステージにいて
Please stay on stage more, forever and ever
私がもし 君の元 離れたなら
If I were to leave your side...
君はちょっと 寂しくなるかな 意地悪考える
I wonder if you'd be a little lonely; I think mischievous thoughts
好きな人が いるのなら 内緒にして
If you have someone you like, keep it a secret
ねえ 神様 将来の指輪 どこかに隠してて
Hey God, please hide the future wedding ring somewhere
君の好きに 合わせたんだ 髪の色
I matched my hair color to your preference
私の中 君抜けて
You've left me
あと数パーセント どこへ
Where did the remaining few percent go?
責任とってね 大好きです
Take responsibility, I love you
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Please never quit being an idol
優しい目も 真面目な顔も 全て知ってる 私が言う
Your kind eyes, your serious face; I say this because I know them all
絶対そのまま 輝いて
Please keep shining just as you are
星を持つ者が 放つ甘い魔法
The sweet magic cast by those who hold the stars
眩しい君が 世界一だよ
You, dazzling, are the best in the world
君の夢はなんですか？
What is your dream?
教えてほしい
I want you to tell me
その夢がアイドルじゃなくても
Even if that dream isn't being an idol
覚悟はしてるから
I'm prepared for it
星のいない空
A sky without stars
それが当たり前で
That's only natural
暗い道に目が慣れずに
Without my eyes adjusting to the dark path
踏み出すのも怖かった
I was even afraid to take a step forward
そんな時 やっと見えた光
In those times, a light I finally saw
絶対君が歌ってて
You must definitely keep singing
嫌だの我儘と分かってても
Even though I know it's a selfish "no"
君はキラキラ 一生が似合う
You look best sparkling for a lifetime
絶対大きなステージで
Definitely on a big stage
一列でも前で感じたい
I want to feel you even one row closer
今日の歌い方 なんか好きだな
I kind of like the way you're singing today
君の努力 証の愛
Your effort is proof of love
成り立つこの関係は
This relationship that holds together
強くて脆いな
Is strong yet fragile
星の幸せを願った
I prayed for the star's happiness
だけど
But...
でもね だって君はアイドルよ
But you know, because you're an idol
ずっと
Always
初めて目が合った日から
Since the day our eyes first met
今日も明日も君ばかりだ
Today and tomorrow, it's only you
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Don't ever quit being an idol
（ずっと）
(Always)
これは報われない御伽話
This is a fairy tale that won't be rewarded
恋よりももっと好きだ
I like you even more than love
魔法よ解けないままで
Magic, please don't ever break
(Unhappy?)
悩める人の子よ
You troubled child
(Unlucky?)
人ならざる者も
Even those who aren't human
(Be happy!)
弛まず目指せよ
Aim for it without slacking
(Undead!)
生きていんだろ
You're still alive after all
目逸らした過去も
The past you turned your eyes from
退屈な涙も
And the boring tears too
カウンセリング やれやれ
Counseling, good grief
古今東西 ツギハギ
All times and places, patchwork
(Unhappy? Unlucky? Be happy! Undead! Undead! Undead!)
ねえねえねえ なんだかどうして
Hey, hey, hey, why is it
戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
I feel like I'm fighting something
触れられない傷跡も
Even the scars that can't be touched
過去の自分 自分 自分 自分と もう
With my past self, self, self, self, already...
とっくに死んでる
I'm long dead
透明な亡霊と対決
A confrontation with a transparent ghost
痛い痛いで痛い記憶の
Ouch, ouch, from the painful memories
ノックの音
The sound of knocking
残念 もういないのに
Too bad, even though they're not here anymore
あれ？そっちが良い？アイロニーね
Huh? You like that better? How ironic
逃かされているのは 現在の自分？
Is it my current self who's being let escape?
ナンセンス 消えないレッテル
Nonsense, an indelible label
Yeah 弱はコンプレックス
Yeah, weakness is a complex
取り憑かれているみたい
Seems like I'm being possessed
縋りついたまま
Clinging to it
まだ離れない
Still haven't let go
有りし日の自分
Of who I used to be
死んじゃいない
I'm not dead
お前とお前の連鎖
The chain of you and yourself
生きていることとは変わり続けることだ
Living means to keep on changing
不幸に甘んじて満足するなよ
Don't be content and settle for unhappiness
幸せになろうとしないなんて
Not even trying to be happy...
卑怯だ
Is cowardly
この世 この世は
This world, this world is...
奇怪 奇怪 ファンタジー
A strange, strange fantasy
次は鬼が出るか 蛇が出るか
Will a demon or a snake appear next?
出会って違って
Meeting and being different
やっと始まる物語
The story finally begins
さあ 人か化物か
Now, is it a human or a monster?
古今東西 ツギハギ
All times and places, patchwork
Past & Future...
can't change the Past
run for the Future
カットイン
Cut-in!
なんだかどうして
For some reason, why...
未来になんぞ何の
To a future of whatever...
希望も持てない
I can't even have hope
ような気がしても
Even if it feels that way
随分言ってる既視感とテンプレで爆笑
Bursting into laughter at the clichés and déjà vu
素敵な出来事も気配もない
Not a sign of any wonderful events
残念 詰んだ経験の因果
Too bad, the karma of accumulated experience
形骸化された神話と退屈な進化
An empty myth and a boring evolution
要は刺激が欲しいんだ
In short, I want stimulation
飽きちゃった
I'm bored
慣れちゃった
I've gotten used to it
なんて 整っていくガイダンス
Such is the guidance that takes shape
増えるコンプライアンス
Increasing compliance
蓋されていくみたい
Feels like I'm being capped off
吸い尽くして
Sucking it all dry
あれもこれもどれも同じ味がする
This, that, and everything tastes the same
死んじゃいない
I'm not dead
お前とお前の連鎖
The chain of you and yourself
何時の世も過去も未来も
At any age, past or future
現在にあるんだ
They all exist in the present
生きていることを率直に果たせよ
Simply fulfill the act of being alive
目指せ happiesuto
Aim to be the happiest
死んじゃいない
I'm not dead
お前に言っているんだ
I'm talking to you
幸せを諦めてしまうな 人で在れば
If you're human, don't give up on happiness
ただ苦しみに慣れて耐えているだけじゃ
If you're just enduring and used to the pain
死んでいるも同然
You might as well be dead
屍のアンデッド
A corpse-like undead
人ならざる者も 弛まず目指せよ
Even those who aren't human, aim for it without slacking
生きていんだろ
You're still alive after all
そこに向かうも 幸せなものも
The path you head on, and the happy things...
全部全部お前だ
It's all you, every single bit.
古今東西...
All times and places...
Reversible
ヒビカセ
Hibikase (Resonate)
真夜中に告ぐ音の警告
A sound gives its warning in the middle of the night
共鳴音に酔う午前零時
I'm intoxicated by the resonance at midnight
貴方が触れる高まる熱
You're touching the heat that's increasing
指先に踊らされて
Dancing at the fingertips
感覚 即 体感
Sensation, then actual experience
寝静まる夜 二人だけの密
The quiet night, a secret for just the two of us
体感 即 快感
Actual experience, then pleasure
重なる波形に魅了されていく
I'm being charmed by the overlapping waveforms
忘れないでね 私の声を
Don't forget my voice
画面越しでいい ちゃんと愛して
It's fine even if it's through the screen, love me properly
バーチャルだって突き放さないで
Don't push me away even if I'm virtual
貴方の音にまだ溺れていたい
I want to still be drowning in your sound
覚えていてね 私の声を
Remember my voice
貴方がくれたこの身全てを
Everything about this body you gave me
見つめ合う貴方と二人
The two of us staring at each other
重ねた息と音と響かせ
Resonating with the overlapped breath and sound
真夜中に問う冷え切った熱
A midnight question to the chilled heat
待ち続けてる午前零時
12 AM that I keep waiting for
鏡映しに飽和していく
Being saturated by the mirror image
知らない音が伝う
Unknown sounds are being transmitted
感覚 即 体感
Sensation, then actual experience
寝静まる夜と息遣い揃う
The quiet night and breathing match up
体感 即 快感
Actual experience, then pleasure
錆びたロジック「今一度」を焦がれる
The rusted logic, I'm yearning for "one more time"
忘れないでね 私の声を
Don't forget my voice
次元も超えて飛ばすシグナル
Sending signals across dimensions
バーチャルだなんて言わないで
Don't say that it's virtual
貴方の音にまだ愛されていたい
I want to still be loved by your sound
覚えていてね 私の声を
Remember my voice
貴方がくれたこの身全てを
Everything about this body you gave me
言の葉と初の音が交わる
The words and the sound of the beginning intersect
この息と音と響かせ
Resonating with this breath and sound
ヒビカセ
Resonate
貴方の産んだ音にただ恋をしていたの
I was just in love with the sound you created
悲しみ怒り関心全て打ち鳴らす
Ringing out all the sorrow, anger, and interest
絶えず叫ぶ声連ねる
A continuously shouting voice, connecting
余熱交ぜる愛、絶え艶めく
Mixing the remaining heat, love, it shines intensely
絶えず叫ぶ声連ねる
A continuously shouting voice, connecting
余熱交ぜる愛、絶え艶めく
Mixing the remaining heat, love, it shines intensely
魅了されていく
I'm being charmed
忘れないでね 私の声を
Don't forget my voice
画面越しでいい ちゃんと愛して
It's fine even if it's through the screen, love me properly
バーチャルだって突き放さないで
Don't push me away even if I'm virtual
貴方の音にまだ溺れていたい
I want to still be drowning in your sound
覚えていてね 私の声を
Remember my voice
貴方がくれたこの身全てを
Everything about this body you gave me
見つめ合う貴方と二人
The two of us staring at each other
重ねた息と音を響かせ
Resonating with the overlapped breath and sound
貴方の初の音 この声聞かせ
Resonate, this voice of the beginning that you gave me
音響かせ、音響かせ
Resonate the sound, resonate the sound
ヒビカセ
Resonate
Reversible
はい！
Yes!
というわけで！
So then!
皆さん、新衣装になりました！
Everyone, I've got a new outfit!
どうですかー？
How is it?
かっこいいですかー？
Is it cool?
なんと、今回は
You see, this time
ダンスを頑張ると決めた、その時から決めていた...
I decided to work hard on dancing, and since then I've decided...
ちょっとカッコいい系のダンス衣装になってみました！
to try a slightly cool-style dance outfit!
イエーイ！
Yay!
皆さん写真いっぱい撮って撮って撮って撮って！
Everyone, take lots of pictures, take them, take them!
イエーイ、かっこいいでしょう？
Yay, isn't it cool?
さっきから「可愛い」ばっかなんだけど、かっこいいはどこ行ったんだよ！
You've only been saying "cute", where did the "cool" go?!
おい！かっこいいはどこ行ったんだよ！
Hey! Where did the "cool" go?!
はい！というわけで新衣装になりました。
Okay! So, that's the new outfit.
ゲストパートの「絶対アイドル辞めないで」から、
From the guest part "Zettai Idol Yamenaide",
あの、ソロになりまして、
well, I went solo,
「アンデッド」「ヒビカセ」と続けてお送りさせていただきました。
and performed "Undead" and "Hibikase" back-to-back.
どうでしたか？
How was it?
めっちゃ頑張って、
I worked really hard,
「足千切れそう」ってそういうことです、本当に。
and my legs felt like they were gonna fall off, for real.
たくさん今回は
This time, for the transformation,
変身のために飛びました。足が千切れそうです。
I jumped a lot. My legs feel like they're falling off.
「絶対アイドル辞めないで」も、先輩方、そしてラプラス殿も来てくれて、
For "Zettai Idol Yamenaide", my seniors and La+-dono came out,
ありがとう！激ムズだったね、本当に。
thank you! It was super tough, really.
本当に激ムズでしたね。
It really was super tough.
皆さん、一緒に頑張ってくださり、本当にありがとうございました！
Everyone, thank you so much for working hard with me!
そしてですね、この後もまだまだゲストさんたくさん呼んでおります！
And also, I've invited many more guests after this!
そして、ござるも、
And, I also...
実はこのカラーリングだけじゃないんですよ！
actually have more than just this coloring!
なので、そちらも公開していくので、皆様お楽しみに！
So I'll be revealing that too, please look forward to it!
それでは、次はゲストさんと一緒に歌わせていただきます。
Now, for the next song, I'll be singing with a guest.
それでは、どうぞ！
Here it is!
Black Rock Shooter
どこへ行ったの？
Where did you go?
聞こえますか？
Can you hear me?
あとどれだけ叫べばいいのだろう
How much more do I have to scream?
あとどれだけ泣けばいいのだろう
How much more do I have to cry?
もうやめて わたしはもう走れない
Stop it already, I can't run anymore
いつか夢見た世界が閉じる
The world I once dreamed of is closing
真っ暗で明かりもない
It's pitch black with no light
崩れかけたこの道で
On this crumbling road
あるはずもないあの時の希望が見えた気がした
I felt like I saw the hope from that time that shouldn't exist
どうして
Why?
Black Rock Shooter
懐かしい記憶
Nostalgic memories
ただ楽しかったあの頃を
Those days when it was just fun
Black Rock Shooter
でも動けないよ
But I can't move
闇を駆ける星に願いを
A wish to the star racing through the darkness
もう一度だけ走るから
Because I'll run just one more time
怖くて震える声でつぶやく
I whisper in a voice trembling with fear
わたしの名前を呼んで
Call my name
夜明けを抱く空 境界線までの距離
The sky embracing the dawn, the distance to the boundary line
あと一歩届かない
One more step and I won't reach it
こらえた涙があふれそうなの
The tears I held back are about to overflow
今下を向かないで 止まってしまう
Don't look down now, or you'll stop
未来を生きていたいんだ わかったの
I want to live in the future, I understand now
思い出して 強く強く信じるの
Remember, believe strongly, strongly
そうよ
That's right
Black Rock Shooter
優しい匂い
A gentle scent
痛いよ 辛いよ
It hurts, it's hard
飲み込む言葉
Words I swallow
最初から
From the very beginning...
分かっていた
I already knew
ここにいることを
that I would be here.
私の中の
Inside of me,
すべての勇気が
all of my courage
火を灯して
is lighting a fire.
もう逃げないよ
I won't run away anymore.
ブラックロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter,
一人じゃないよ
you're not alone.
声を上げて
Raise your voice,
泣いたって構わない
it's okay to cry.
ブラックロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter,
見ていてくれる
you're watching over me.
今から
Starting now,
始まるの
it begins—
私の物語
my story.
忘れそうになったら
If I'm ever about to forget,
この歌を
this song...
歌うの
I'll sing it.
息つまるばかりで
Just feeling stifled,
温い退屈な夜道で
on this lukewarm, boring night road.
Mellow, mellow, mellow
ルールは無視で行きたいね
I want to go on ignoring the rules.
ha-ha
So burn, my burn, my heart
Uh
悟られそう
It looks like I'll be found out.
uh
可か不可 get down now
Pass or fail, get down now.
Uh
あーあ
Ah, ah
I know the way
願ってるばっかじゃ叶わない
Just wishing won't make it come true.
めちゃくちゃにされたって 変わらない
Even if it's messed up, it won't change.
まあね 喰らえ 覚醒 Find the way
Well then, eat this! Awakening, find the way.
願ってるばっかじゃ叶わない
Just wishing won't make it come true.
めちゃくちゃにされたって 変わらない
Even if it's messed up, it won't change.
まあね 喰らえ 覚醒 Find the way
Well then, eat this! Awakening, find the way.
待ってライトあびる感覚
Wait, the feeling of being in the spotlight...
甘い罠 見当違い
Sweet traps and wrong estimations.
disも聞き飽きたわ そりゃね
I'm tired of hearing the disses, naturally.
いけるところまで Take me higher どう？
Take me higher as far as I can go, how's that?
I know the way
願ってるばっかじゃ叶わない
Just wishing won't make it come true.
めちゃくちゃにされたって 変わらない
Even if it's messed up, it won't change.
まあね 喰らえ 覚醒 Find the way
Well then, eat this! Awakening, find the way.
もうずっとちゃんといわなきゃ
I have to say it properly now.
それは誰のせい
Whose fault is that?
終わらない夢を 描こう 描いて願ったまま
Let's draw an endless dream as we wished.
欲しがったまま 欲しがったまま
Still wanting it, still wanting it...
終わらない夜を 越えて行こう 越えて行こう
Let's cross the endless night, cross it...
このまま 焦がれた向こう側へ
just like this, to the side we yearned for.
ぶっちゃけ気にしてない 嘘さ 何でも言っていい
Honestly, I don't care—no, say whatever you want.
運命感じる 感受性 痛めない うちも負けない
Feeling destiny, I won't lose either.
追っていつでもナンバーワン
Always chasing to be number one.
Go beyond the way!
息つまるばかりで
Just feeling stifled,
ずるい言葉を捜して
searching for unfair words.
歩みを解き放し
Unleashing our steps,
追い上げていけ
let's catch up and go!
How we are the winner
So burn, my burn, my heart
Uh uh uh uh
終わらない夢を 描こう 描いて願ったまま
Let's draw an endless dream as we wished.
欲しがったまま 欲しがったまま
Still wanting it, still wanting it...
終わらない夜を 越えて行こう 越えて行こう
Let's cross the endless night, cross it...
このまま 焦がれた向こう側へ
just like this, to the side we yearned for.
追いかけて 合わせた背が熱くて
Chasing after, the backs we aligned are hot.
もう一生離れない
Won't separate for a lifetime.
限界の向こう側へ
To the other side of our limits!
Ready, steady,
you go beyond the way
はい。というわけで、
Yes. So,
本日はこのお二人に
today I have these two
来ていただきましたー！
guests here with me!
わああー！
Waaaah!
せーの、お誕生日おめでとうー！
One, two, Happy Birthday!
やったー！ありがとうございます！
Yay! Thank you so much!
お忙しいのに、お二人とも今日は
Even though you're busy, both of you today...
てか、もうずっとレッスンからか。
Well, you've been with me since the lessons.
本当にお付き合いいただきましてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for joining me!
こちらこそありがとうございましたー！
Thank you as well!
今回はですね、誕生日で、実は衣装が...
This time, for my birthday, my outfit is actually...
新しくて可愛い！
It's new and cute!
見て見て！めちゃめちゃ可愛い！
Look, look! It's so cute!
おへそ、おへそ見えちゃってる！
Your belly button, your belly button is showing!
そう、やべ、取られる。
Yeah, oh no, it'll be stolen.
後ろ可愛い！このフード、めちゃめちゃ可愛い！
The back is cute! This hood is so cute!
あとツインテールが似合ってる！
And the twin tails suit you!
イェーイ！そうなんです。
Yay! That's right.
新しくね、ダンスする用みたいな衣装になったので。
It's a new outfit meant for dancing.
これは... 恐れ多くも、ダンスが上手いお二人を
So... I thought I'd humbly call on you two,
呼んでもいいかな？って言って、
who are so good at dancing,
呼ばせていただきました！
and invited you here!
あなた方です！
It's you guys!
めちゃめちゃ楽しかった！
It was so much fun!
レッスンもね、一緒に頑張っていただきまして。
We worked hard together in the lessons too.
お二人ともめちゃめちゃ元がいいから、
Since you two are naturally so good,
風真一人だけどうしようかな、これ...
I was worried about being the only one...
二人呼んで大丈夫だったかな...って。
if it was okay to call you two.
めっちゃ踊ったよ。
We danced a lot.
最高なものができたと思います。
I think we made something great.
かっこよかったかな？
Was it cool?
今頃コメントには「めっちゃ良かったよ」が流れてると思います。
I bet the comments are full of "It was so good" right now.
だって、ばえちゃんと初めてじゃん！
Because it's the first time with Bae-chan!
一緒にダンスするの。
Dancing together like this.
フォーメーションダンス！
Formation dance!
めちゃめちゃ嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
誘ってよかったー！
I'm so glad I invited you!
お二人と一緒にこの期間一緒に踊って、
Dancing with you two during this period,
めちゃめちゃ勉強になりました、先生方！
I learned so much, teachers!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
また何かあったら是非一緒に踊りましょう！
Let's definitely dance together again sometime!
是非やりましょう！呼んでください！
Let's do it! Please call us!
じゃあちょっとこの記念に、この友情の証、
Then, as a memento of this friendship,
強い、かっこいいポーズで写真撮っとこう。
let's take a photo in a strong, cool pose.
かっこいいポーズ！
Cool pose!
かっこいいポーズ、思いつかない、なんだ！？
I can't think of a cool pose, what should it be!?
なんだ？可愛い、可愛い！
What is it? So cute, so cute!
まいっか。
Oh well.
みんなたくさんSNSに投稿してください！
Everyone, please post a lot on SNS!
はい。と言いつつ、実はですね、
Yes. That said, actually,
もう一つお願いがあって...
I have one more request...
今日、この後、今日初披露のオリ曲があるんですけど...
After this, I have an original song to perform for the first time...
オリ曲ー！？
An original song!?
楽しみだ！どんな曲？
Looking forward to it! What kind of song?
やっぱり風真いろは、かっこよくなりたくて。
After all, Kazama Iroha wants to be cool.
今回は、かっこいい曲を持ってまいりました！
So this time, I brought a cool song!
わああー！楽しみ！
Waaah! Looking forward to it!
お二人から勇気をもらってから行こうかな。
I'll go after getting some courage from you two.
かっこいいビーム！
Cool beam!
ビーム、もらった！
Got the beam!
すごい、なんか心なしかちょっとイケメンになってきた。
Wow, I feel like I'm becoming a bit of a heartthrob.
イケメンのポーズ、こう？
Is this a heartthrob pose?
いいじゃん、かっこいいじゃん！
Nice, you look cool!
イケてる気がする！
I feel like I'm rocking it!
エネルギーもらえたんで、頑張ってきます！
I've got the energy, so I'll go give it my all!
いってらっしゃーい！
Go for it!
お二人とも今日はお祝いと、
Thank you both so much for the celebration,
そして一緒に歌って踊ってくれて、
for singing and dancing with me,
そして応援ビームはありがとうございました！
and for the support beam!
また遊びましょうね！
Let's hang out again!
それでは、この後新オリ曲初披露させていただきます。
Well then, I'll now perform my new original song.
せーの、どーぞー！
One, two, please enjoy!
見た目だけじゃワカラナイ ホントの私
The real me that you can't tell just by looking
ワタシのこと可愛いだけど
You might think I'm cute, but
まさか思っていないよね？
You don't think that's all, do you?
ワタシの本当...
My true...
真実...
Truth...
知っていてほしい
I want you to know
Emotion Emotion
Glowing Emotion
予測誤差の範囲と
Within the range of prediction error,
不測の事態も動じない
unfazed even by unforeseen circumstances.
おすましフェイスでいるけど
I keep a composed face,
心は常に青白く燃え
but my heart is always burning pale blue.
諦めはしない
I won't give up.
媚びたりもしない
I won't flatter either.
ワタシを曲げない
I won't bend myself.
扱いやすいヤツだと思って
Thinking I'm an easy one to handle,
あまく見てると
if you underestimate me,
痛い目見るぞ
you'll have a hard time.
それでも
Even so...
ときには逃げ出してしまいたい
sometimes I want to run away.
そんな衝動に
At such an impulse,
弱音吐きたくなる
wanting to whine,
真夜中もある
there are midnights too.
ほんの小さな小さな妥協が
Just a tiny, tiny compromise
積み重なり重なって動けない
piles up until I can't move,
大きな大きな可能性なくし
losing big, big possibilities,
未来を狭めてしまうから
and narrowing down the future.
Passion
どんなに暗くても辛くても後悔だけはしない
No matter how dark or painful, I won't regret.
Emotion
イケてるのは見た目じゃなくて生きかたなんだ
Being cool isn't about looks, it's about life.
現実と理想との
Even if I could shorten
距離を縮められたとしても
the distance between reality and ideals,
おすましフェイスでいるだけ
I'd just keep a composed face,
何事もなかったかのように
as if nothing had happened.
立ち止まりはしない
I won't stop.
後戻りもない
There's no going back.
夢を捨てない
I won't throw away my dreams.
らしいとからしくないとか決めつけないで
Don't decide what's 'like me' or 'not like me',
全部がワタシ
because all of it is me.
それでも
Even so,
ときには温もりが恋しい
sometimes I miss the warmth.
そんな感情に
In such emotions,
流されてしまいそうな
almost being swept away,
真夜中もある
there are midnights too.
こんな甘い甘いことだけ
I don't need a weakness
求めししまうような弱さいらない
that seeks only such sweet things.
苦い苦い経験だって
Because even bitter experiences
ワタシを強くしてくれるから
will make me stronger.
Passion
Emotion
これがこれがワタシの
This is, this is my...
真実
truth.
とても狭い狭い世界の中だけで
I don't want to end it
終わらせたくはないんだ
only within a very narrow world.
広い広い世界の果てまで
To the ends of the wide world,
駆け抜けて生きていくんだから
I'm going to run through and live.
Passion
どんなに険しくて過酷でも楽しんでやるさ
Even if it's harsh and cruel, I'll enjoy it.
Emotion
イケてるのは見た目じゃなくて生きかたなんだから
Being cool isn't about looks, it's about life!
はい、というわけで、皆さん、
Alright then, everyone!
ゲストパートから続けて新オリ曲
Following the guest part,
「ホントノワタシ」歌って踊らせていただきました！
I sang and danced to my new original song, 'Honto no Watashi'!
なんと風真いろは、
Believe it or not,
7曲目のオリ曲です！
this is Kazama Iroha's 7th original song!
そしてオリ曲のジャケットも届いているので
And the original song's jacket art has arrived,
見ていきましょう。こちらです！
so let's take a look. Here it is!
はい、こちらの風真いろは新オリ曲7曲目
Yes, this 7th original song by Kazama Iroha,
「ホントノワタシ」は、
called 'Honto no Watashi'...
日付変わりまして19日0時よりリリースされることとなりました！
...will be released at midnight on the 19th!
今回の新衣装にちなんでこちら作っていただきました！
This was created in connection with my new outfit!
ちょっと今までとだいぶ系統の違う曲になるんですけど、
It's a song with a very different style from my usual ones.
あの、いつもみんなね、ありがたいことに
Um, since everyone usually—and I'm grateful for this—
風真いろはのこと「かっこいい」っていうより「かわいい」って言ってくださる方がいっぱいいらっしゃるので、
says I'm 'cute' rather than 'cool'...
「いや、かっこいいところもあるんだよ」っていうのを
I wanted to convey that 'hey, I have a cool side too,'
伝えたくて作らせていただきました。
so I had this song made.
こちらぜひ0時にリリースされたらたくさん聴いて、
Please listen to it a lot once it's released at midnight,
またハッシュタグの見てみいろはなので感想とか教えていただけたら嬉しいです！
and I'd love to hear your thoughts using the hashtag #Mitemi_Iroha!
そしてそして、ゲストパートについても
And now, about the guest part,
お話ししていきましょうかね。じゃあ戻って、
let's talk about that too. Moving back...
はい、ゲストでね、ミオ先輩と、
Yes, as guests, Mio-senpai,
そしてハジメちゃん、べー先輩と一緒に歌って踊らせていただきました！
Hajime-chan, and Bae-senpai sang and danced with me!
ミオ先輩、そしてべーちゃん、そしてハジメちゃん、
Mio-senpai, Bae-chan, and Hajime-chan,
来てくれてありがとう！
thank you so much for coming!
もう本当に歌も難しかったし、
The song was really difficult,
もうべー...
and Bae...
始めて、始めちゃんたちに関してはマジこれができなさすぎて
Starting with Hajime-chan and the others, I seriously couldn't do this...
一生やりすぎて
I overdid it so much...
一生腰痛を抱えて、これが結構筋肉痛の原因でした。
...that I had constant back pain; it was a major cause of my muscle soreness.
はい。
Yes.
でもすごい、一緒に歌って躍らせていただきまして、
But I had an amazing time singing and dancing with them,
とってもとってもいい経験になりました。
and it was a very, very good experience.
皆さんありがとうございました。
Thank you so much, everyone.
はい。
Yes.
というわけで、次の曲に行く前に、
So, before moving on to the next song,
お水飲んでいいですか？
can I have some water?
お水飲みます。
I'm going to drink some water.
お水。
Water.
ロゴも見て、実は変わってた。
Look at the logo, too. It actually changed.
よし。
Alright.
お待たせしました。
Sorry to keep you waiting.
息整えて
Let me catch my breath...
はい、
Yes,
次の曲なんですけれども、
about the next song...
やっぱりみんなバラードも好きだよって言ってくれる
Many people tell me they like ballads too,
方が多いので、今回の生誕ライブ、
so for this birthday live,
バラードやろうと思って持ってきました。
I decided to bring a ballad to perform.
はい。
Yes.
ちょっとかっこいい感じに歌えるか
I practiced a lot to see if I could sing it
色々練習したんですけど、
in a somewhat cool style,
ぜひ心を込めて歌うので、
and I'll sing it with all my heart,
聴いていただけると嬉しいです。
so I'd be happy if you'd listen.
それでは次の曲お聴きください。
Please listen to the next song.
W/X/Y
垂れ流した
The sound of the TV
テレビの音
left on,
溜めてしまった
the laundry
洗濯物は今日こそ
I'd accumulated, today of all days,
晴れでもあえて
even if it's sunny,
外には出ないでいよう
let's not go out.
映えないスナックと
With unphotogenic snacks
アルコールで乾杯をしよう
and alcohol, let's make a toast.
二人、酸いも甘いも
The two of us, through sweet and bitter,
噛み合わないとしても
though we don't always click,
お互い寄り添うように 少しずらしてみようよ
let's lean on each other and drift a little.
君がくれた太陽
The sun you gave me,
月で隠れないよう
don't let it hide behind the moon,
輝き満ちるように歌うメロディ
the melody of our shining song.
戯れる Slowly flowing
Play, slowly flowing,
愛してるも通り越して
even the love, passing through,
似た者同士 こうして
kindred spirits, like this,
年老いるまで笑っていたいね
let's keep laughing until we grow old.
君がいなきゃ lonely lonely day
If you aren't here, it's a lonely, lonely day,
夢の中 Fall asleep in bed
in my dreams, I fall asleep in bed,
起こすから morning call で
and I'll wake you with a morning call,
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
脱ぎっぱなしの
If I follow the footprints
足跡辿ると
left behind,
不意を突いて
you catch me by surprise
後ろから抱きつくの
and hug me from behind.
つい、繰り返すと
As we keep repeating this,
忘れしまいそうになるよ
I feel like I might forget
振り返った
that the days
日々が当たり前じゃないこと
I look back on aren't guaranteed.
二人対の細胞
The two of us, a pair of cells,
絡み合う特別を
entwining in something special,
噛み締めて生きたいと思った まどろみ抱く正午
I want to cherish life like this, in a midday doze.
吐息漏れた体温
Your body heat and sighing breath,
微塵も逃さないよう
I won't let even a bit slip away,
頭の中刻む甘いメモリ
carving sweet memories into my mind.
戯れる Slowly flowing
Play, slowly flowing,
愛してるも通り越して
even the love, passing through,
違う者同士 こうして
different people, like this,
年老いるまで笑っていたいね
let's keep laughing until we grow old.
君がいなきゃ lonely lonely day
If you aren't here, it's a lonely, lonely day,
夢の中 Fall asleep in bed
in my dreams, I fall asleep in bed,
起こすから morning call で
and I'll wake you with a morning call,
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
重ねた手は離さないでいて
Please don't let go of our joined hands.
ごめん、これそばに居たいだけ
Sorry, I just want to be by your side.
抱えた想いはお互い様でしょ
Our feelings are mutual, right?
ほら、おあいこでしょ
See, we're even.
すれ違い、間違いもあるし
There are misunderstandings and mistakes,
筋書き通りいかない
things don't go as planned,
打診、悲しみだって半分こにしよう
let's share the testing times and the sadness.
別れない希望 独りよがりにならないように
Hoping we never part, so I won't be self-centered,
いつも...
always...
君がいなきゃ今もどこかで
If you weren't here, even now somewhere
動けないままの僕で
I'd be unable to move,
ありがとうを伝えたいのです
so I want to say thank you.
ありがとうを伝えたいのですよ
I want to tell you my gratitude
これからは僕が支えてくって
That I'll support you from now on
呆れてしまうくらいにね
To the point you'll be dumbfounded
愛が増していく day by day
Love increases day by day
面と向かうとどうしても
When we face each other, somehow
素直になれないな、ごめんね
I can't be honest, I'm sorry
戯れる Slowly flowing
Playing around, slowly flowing
愛してるも通り越して
Even beyond saying "I love you"
似た者同士こうして
Two of a kind, like this
年老いるまで笑っていたいね
I want to be laughing until we grow old
君がいなきゃ lonely lonely day
If you're not here, it's a lonely, lonely day
夢の中 fall asleep
In a dream, fall asleep
起こすから morning callで
I'll wake you up with a morning call
I protect you from nightmares, Baby
ありがとうございました
Thank you very much
はい、それではですね
Yes, well then...
皆さん、これ聴いていただきまして 本当にありがとうございます
Everyone, thank you so much for listening to this
はい、こんなに歌わせていただいたんですけども
Yes, I got to sing this much, but...
バラード、なかなか 3Dライブでやらないので すごく緊張しました
I don't often do ballads in 3D lives, so I was very nervous
どうだったでしょうか
How was it?
あ、めっちゃ拍手とめっちゃいいってやつが見える ありがとうございます
Ah, I can see so many claps and "it was great" comments, thank you
そしてここで、皆さんお持ちかねの あの告知を挟ませていただければと思います
And here, I'd like to share that announcement you've all been waiting for
それでは元気に行きます
Alright, let's do this with energy!
それではドン！ 風真いろは誕生日記念2025誕生日記念グッズ出ましたー！
Here we go! Kazama Iroha Birthday Celebration 2025 Birthday Goods are out!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ビジュアルが大変よろしい
The visual is very nice
こちらのグッズが販売決定です
These goods are confirmed for sale
はい、というわけで詳細を見ていきましょう ドン！
Yes, so let's look at the details. Bam!
はい、まず1つ目は回転アクリルスタンド
Yes, first is the Rotating Acrylic Stand
イラストはNardack先生に描いていただきました
The illustration was drawn by Nardack-sensei
こちらですね、あのこういうことです あの、裏表になってるって言いたい
This one, it's like this... I want to say it has a front and back
裏表になってる
It's double-sided
そう、あのカラーライズ衣装とこの新しい新衣装で
Yes, with the Colorize costume and this new costume...
裏表になってます
It's double-sided
クルクル回せるので ござるの事も回して遊んでください
Since it can be rotated, please play by spinning de-gozaru too
よろしくお願いします
Thank you
はい、温感湯呑み
Yes, Thermal Teacup
これついさっきサンプルが控え室に届いて試しました
A sample arrived in the waiting room just now and I tried it
あのちゃんと温かいの入れるとフワーってですね
When you put something warm in, it goes "fwaa"...
ちゃんとポコべが浮き出てござるが打ち合わせとかね
Pokobe appears properly, and when de-gozaru is in a meeting...
リハやってる間に湯が冷めきってちゃんと緑に戻っておりました
The water cooled down during rehearsal and it returned to green
こちらもすごく可愛くてお寿司屋さんとかにあるサイズなのかな
This is also very cute, is it like the size they have at sushi restaurants?
結構大きめのちゃんとした湯呑みです
It's a fairly large, proper teacup
是非ね、使ってもらえたら嬉しいです
I'd be happy if you used it
はい、風真いろは、新 こちらポップダンス衣装って名前なんですけど
Yes, Kazama Iroha, new... this is called the Pop Dance costume...
のぬいぐるみです！
It's a plushie!
是非お迎えしてほしいな
I'd really like you to welcome it
ござるさんのぬいぐるみでみんな遊んでくれ！
Everyone, please play with the de-gozaru plushie!
ということで、このツインテールのね新衣装なんとぬいぐるみになりました
So, this twin-tailed new costume has actually become a plushie
あの手持ちじゃなくて、こうこういうタイプだったかな
Not a handheld one, I think it was this type?
だと思うので是非ねみんなのおうちに飾ってもらえたら嬉しいです
So I'd be happy if everyone displayed it in their homes
はい、なんとござるのこれ、これとお揃いのこれが出ます
Yes, surprisingly, de-gozaru's this... this and a matching this will come out
ちょっと待って、言い直し
Wait a second, let me say that again
これとお揃いのネックレスが出ます
A matching necklace to this will come out
はい、普段ねアクセサリーとか付けない隊士さんにね
Yes, for the Corps members who don't usually wear accessories...
付けないよーっていう方も、ま良かったらこちらね
Those who say "I don't wear them", if you'd like, this one...
さっきのぬいぐるみにあの括って一緒にセットにして飾っていただいたりとか
You can tie it to the plushie from earlier and display them as a set...
イベントの時に付けてきてもらえたら嬉しいです
Or I'd be happy if you wore it to events
お洒落です、ござると一緒にお揃いに良かったらしましょう
It's stylish, so let's match with de-gozaru if you'd like
というわけで、そしてフルセットがこんな感じ
So, and the full set looks like this
うわー、なんだか爽やかですね
Wow, it looks somewhat refreshing
そう、ライブタイトルの通りリバーシブルなんでね色々ちょっと反転反転がついてたりします
Yes, just like the live title "Reversible", there are various reversals included
そして購入特典はこちら
And the purchase bonus is here
この戦争を終わらせに来ました
I came to end this war
今回はですね、グッズが2種類出るということで数量限定はせずに
This time, since there are two types of goods, they won't be limited quantity...
ちょっと変わった特典にしてみました
I tried making it a bit of a different bonus
こちらは裏表のタロットカードがついてきます
This one comes with a double-sided tarot card
片面にはね、風真の、えっと複製サインとメッセージが入っております
One side has Kazama's, um, duplicate signature and message
...楽しんでもらえたら嬉しいです。
...I hope you'll enjoy it.
数量限定とかではないのでゆっくりね、あの、購入していただければと思います。
It's not limited quantity, so please take your time buying it.
販売開始時間がこの後21時なんですけど、
Sales start at 9:00 PM after this, but...
ちょっと生配信の関係上、ちょっと生配信延びる可能性の方が今大なので、
since the stream might run over, there's a high chance it'll be late,
生配信中に皆さん、あの、カート見に行ってください。
so please go check out the cart during the stream.
あ、でも、あの、数量限定とかないので安心してください。
Oh, but don't worry, it's not a limited quantity item.
はい、そして、フルセットの特典もう一つあります。
Alright, and there's one more full set bonus.
こちらです。
It's this one.
はい、みんな大好きホロカのカードが1枚付いてきます！
Yes, it comes with one Hololive Official Card!
はい、皆さん、よかったらお手に取って、ホロカ勢の皆さんは使ってくださいね。
So please get it, and for those who play the card game, please use it.
遊び方とか、あとカードの詳細は、
For how to play and card details...
hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAMEの公式ホームページにてご確認ください！
please check the Hololive Official Card Game website!
よし、今台本めっちゃ見た。言えなかったらヤバイと思って。
Alright, I looked at the script a lot. I thought it'd be bad if I messed up.
そして、こちら、一緒にこの入れさせていただくカードは、日本語版のみとなっておりますので、ご了承ください。
Also, the cards included will be in Japanese only, so please be aware of that.
はい。カートのオープンですが、こちらですね、100万人記念グッズと誕生日記念グッズ、両方同時なので、よろしくお願いします。
The cart opens for both the 1M milestone and birthday goods simultaneously. Thank you.
ちょっと、ごめんなさい、生配信押しちゃってごめんね。
I'm sorry the stream is running long.
ホロメンも、ホロメンも配信をしててすみません！
Sorry to the other Holo-members who are also streaming!
はい。というわけで、ちょっとお水飲みます。
Anyway, I'm going to drink some water.
はい。
Okay.
はい、というわけで、あと最後のお知らせとしまして、この後本編終了次第、
So, as for the final announcement, after the main stream ends...
ちょっとまた時間がね、確定じゃない、15分からか20分からか、どっちかになると思うんですけど、
the time isn't set, it'll be around 15 or 20 minutes past,
風真いろはのメンバーシップ限定のアンコールライブもございますので、
there will be a membership-exclusive encore live for Kazama Iroha!
みんなが見たかったあの曲やこの曲を歌ったり踊ったりしますので、
I'll be singing and dancing to various songs you've wanted to see,
よかったら見に来てください！
so please come and watch!
よろしくお願いします。メンバーシップギフトとか、今日から入ってくださった隊士さんもありがとうございます！
Thank you. And thanks to those who joined the membership today!
はい。そして何と残念なことに、次の曲が、皆さん、このライブ最後の曲となります。
And unfortunately, the next song will be the last one of this live.
えー、皆さん、もう最後は何を歌うか、ある程度予想されている方も多いかと思いますが、
I'm sure many of you have already guessed what I'll be singing last...
改めまして、この度は、風真いろは生誕ライブ2025、お越しくださいまして、本当にありがとうございました！
but once again, thank you so much for coming to Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2025!
そして、あの制作のために一生懸命頑張ってくださったスタッフさんや、ダンスの先生やマネージャーさんや、皆さん、本当に、クリエイターの皆さんも、ありがとうございました！
To the staff, instructors, managers, and creators who worked so hard... thank you all!
あのー、正直、いろいろあった昨年の年末から、ここまで声が戻ってライブができるっていうことが、ほぼ奇跡、
To be honest, it's almost a miracle that my voice recovered enough to perform like this...
なんだったら、もう半分諦めかけていたんですけども、
given everything that happened at the end of last year. I almost gave up.
スタッフの皆さんや、隊士さんたちがすごい支えてくださって、いろんな方に支えられて本日実施することができました。
But thanks to the staff and fans supporting me, I was able to make it happen today.
本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you so much.
正直、まだ、まだ本調子じゃない部分が多いのは正直なところです。
Honestly, I'm still not quite back to 100%.
だけど、今日少しでもこのライブを見て、たくさんの人に元気が一人でも多く届いていればなと思っております。
But I hope this live brings energy to as many people as possible today.
これからもリハビリしながらですが、精一杯頑張って参りますので、皆さんこれからもよろしくお願いします！
I'll keep doing my best while continuing rehab, so please keep supporting me!
はい。というわけで、最後の曲にふさわしいこの曲、皆さん最後に聞いてください。
Now, please listen to this final song.
風真いろは新オリ曲、「君にしか読めない手紙」。
Kazama Iroha's new original song: "A Letter Only You Can Read."
ありがとう書くとしたら
If I were to write "thank you",
毎日になっちゃうくらい
it would probably be every day.
重すぎる私の想いは
My feelings are too heavy,
最後に伝えるね
I'll tell you at the end.
君にしか読めない手紙
作詞：HoneyWorks
作曲・編曲：HoneyWorks, MARUMOCHI
A Letter Only You Can Read
Lyrics: HoneyWorks
Music & Arrangement: HoneyWorks, MARUMOCHI
lalala
拝啓 私を
Dear, to you...
形作った君へ
...who shaped me,
相も変わらず言葉を
as always, I'm...
届け続けています
...continuing to deliver my words.
lalala
拝啓 未来で
Dear, to you...
私待ってる君へ
...who is waiting for me in the future,
響く音に憂いなど
are you spending your days...
お過ごしでしょうか
...without any sorrow in the echoing sounds?
不安が無いなんて
If I were to say there's no anxiety...
多分無かったけど
...that probably wasn't true, but...
私の言葉
my words,
君の言葉
your words...
重なって笑えたんだ
...overlapped, and we were able to laugh.
ありがとう書くとしたら
If I were to write "thank you",
毎日になっちゃうくらい
it would probably be every day.
重すぎる私の想いは
My feelings are too heavy,
最後に伝えるね
I'll tell you at the end.
ありがとう書くとしたら
If I were to write "thank you,"
毎日になっちゃうくらい
It would be enough for every single day.
重すぎる私の想いは
My feelings are too heavy,
最後に伝えるね
So I'll tell you at the very end.
君がいる それだけでさ
Just you being here,
理由になるなんて奇跡
It's a miracle that it's reason enough.
ありがとう 足りないな
A "thank you" isn't enough,
ごまかすよ
So I'll just brush it off.
愛してる
I love you.
魔法石のブレスレット
A magic stone bracelet,
シロツメクサの女王様
The White Clover Queen.
プラスチックだらけの宝石箱でずっと
In a jewelry box full of plastic,
遊べるよ君と
I can play with you forever.
思い出の欠片たち
Fragments of memories,
溢れるこの場所で
In this place where they overflow.
私の言葉 君の言葉 重ねて
Overlapping my words with yours,
笑っていたい
I want to keep smiling.
忘れられる 世界で今
In this world where things are forgotten,
私が選んだ生き方
This is the way of life I've chosen.
手紙をさ 書いたから
Since I've written this letter,
この音に乗せて
I'll put it in this song.
ありがとう書くとしたら
If I were to write "thank you,"
毎日になっちゃうくらい
It would be enough for every single day.
重すぎる私の想いは
My feelings are too heavy,
最後に伝えるね
So I'll tell you at the very end.
君がいる それだけでさ
Just you being here,
理由になるなんて奇跡
It's a miracle that it's reason enough.
ありがとう 足りないな
A "thank you" isn't enough,
ごまかすよ
So I'll just brush it off.
愛してる
I love you.
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
風真いろは
Kazama Iroha
100万人記念
1 Million Subscribers Celebration
7月1日
July 1st
MV公開
Music Video Release
君にしか読めない手紙 / 風真いろは 100万人記念
A Letter Only You Can Read / Kazama Iroha 1 Million Subs Celebration